### **Portfolio**

A MarkDown portfolio built in GitHub Pages with a Jekyll theme.

View the Project on GitHub at https://github.com/

• Click here to download the most recent PDF

# Amanda M. Williams

# Database Administrator/Junior Software Developer

### **About**

#### **Contact Information**

• Phone: (757) 828-5756

• Email: Amandawilliams1915@gmail.com

• Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/amandamwilliams1/

• Github: https://github.com/AmandaMWilliams

#### Education

- Delaware Technical and Community College (January 2018 August 2020)
- Associate of Science Degree

#### **Achievements**

- Graduated Summa Cum Laude (GPA: 4.0)
- President's List (1 Semester)
- Academic Recognition (4 Semesters)

### **Summary**

Experienced Database Administrator and Junior Software Developer with demonstrated ability to work with teams in AGILE environment. Knowledgeable in MySQL via SQL Server Management Studio, and version control management systems using GitCLI and Github. (https://github.com/AmandaMWilliams).

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages:
  - Java, MarkDown, JavaScript, SQL, HTML

#### • Frameworks/Libraries:

• Spring Boot, ReactJS, Angular2

#### Other Skills:

- Git CLI and Version Control Management
- GitHub Pages
- Agile, Scrum methodologies
- Terminal, Bash, Shell
- Test-Driven Development
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Amazon Web Services (AWS): IAM, S3 Buckets
- SOAP Web Authentication mechanisms: OAuth
- SQL Server Management Studio / MySQL

#### Certifications:

- Intermediate SQL certification from Delaware Technical Community College
- Introduction to SQL certification from Delaware Technical Community College
- Completion of Zip Code Wilmington's 12-Week Java Bootcamp
- HTML certification
- Spring Boot certification

### **Personal Projects**

### Heroku Deployed ReactJS ToDo List Web Application

#### **Current State Of Application**

- Heroku Deployed ReactJS ToDo List Web Application is a ToDo list leveraging NodeJS, ReactJS, and Heroku with Node BuildPack.
- This application is maintained in GitHub here.
- The application is a graphical user interface that displays tasks to be completed.
- The Editor used to implement the application was Visual Studio Code (VS Code).

### **Future Implementation State Of Application**

• In the future, I would like implement a RESTful webserver to enable data persistence.

### Angular ToDo List Web Application with SpringBoot

### **Current State of Application**

- Angular Todo List Web Application with SpringBoot is a ToDo list application leveraging Angular, SpringBoot and Heroku.
- This application is maintained in GitHub: Angular, SpringBoot.
- This application is a graphical user interface with Username and Password protection.
- The Editor used to implement the Angular Front End of this Application was Visual Studio Code (VS Code).
- The Editor used to implement the SpringBood Middleware of this Application was IntelliJ CE.

## **Professional Experience**

Diamond Technologies, Inc.

Junior Software Developer Wilmington, DE April 2021 - Current

- Added additional functionality to existing code using .Net, SQL Relational Databases, WordPress, and Microsoft Access.
- Worked individually and with teammates to debug code and resolve functionality errors through database administration.
- Alleviated unassigned ticket backlog average from 10 to 3, and overall open ticket average from 30 to 15 tickets.

### **Zip Code Wilmington**

Software Developer
Wilmington, DE
November 2020 - January 2021

- Admitted in Zip Code Wilmington's highly-competitive software development program which accepts less than 10% of applicants
- Achieved over 1000 hours of software development projects and training in an immersive training program using Agile and Scrum methodologies and principles
- Gained experience in full-stack development with a focus on Java, test-driven development, and objectoriented programming.

### **Delaware Technical and Community College**

Supplemental Instructor
Wilmington, DE
August 2018 - December 2018

- Facilitated supplemental instruction sessions for targeted courses by sharing with students how to effectively study for the course and how to maximize their potential for their academic success.
- Students who participated in optional supplemental instruction averaged one full letter grade higher on tests than those who did not.

### **Laboratory Corporation of America**

Accessionor New Castle, DE July 2017 - October 2017

- Scanned and entered data about lab specimens received for testing from designated laboratory departments or other locations.
- Alleviated a 3-month backlog of unscanned patient records in three weeks.

#### Aetna Life Insurance - Jacksonville

Complaints and Appeals Analyst Jacksonville, FL January 2016 - May 2017

- Processed incoming appeals and resolved more than 50 written customer requests per day.
- Started as a temporary data entry operator and was hired full-time due to high production and efficiency.

### Availity, LLC

Client Services - EDI Call Center Jacksonville, FL January 2014 - January 2016

- Resolved more than 50 client problems daily by actively listening to their concerns, and offering solutions to address their needs.
- Awarded Employee of the Month 3 times as a result of achieving the highest number of customer service calls completed in single-contact, processing the highest number of account request forms, and having the shortest request-resolution timeframe.

Project maintained by **AmandaMWilliams**Hosted on GitHub Pages — Theme by **orderedlist**